Mohd Imran Ansari

ansari.imran83@gmail.com

\$317045885



in linkedin.com/in/mohd-imran-ansari-70ba6b192

Summary

Experienced Email Marketing Specialist with a demonstrated history of working in multiple industries. Skilled in B2C/B2B, Mass Email Marketing, Email Design, Email Marketing Automation, and Email List Building. Strong marketing professional with a Master of Business Administration - MBA focused in International Business from Lucknow University, Lucknow.

Skills - Email Marketing • Marketing Automation • Mass Email Marketing • Email Strategy • MarketSegmentation • Project Delivery • Business-to-Business (B2B) • Social Media Marketing • Digital Marketing • B2C • Performance Analysis • A/B Testing • Email Deliverability • Drip Campaigns

Tools - Hubspot, Klaviyo, Omnisend, MAUTIC, Mailerlite. Mailchimp, Sendgrid, Selzy, Zoho, Klaviyo, Mailercloud, Saleshandy, SFMC, Ongage, Sparkpost, Getresponse.

Experience

Senior Email marketing Specialist

Channel Clarity

Jun 2022 - Feb 2023

Managing Email Deliverability for multiple domains. Setting up an environment to enable mass emailing for GMAIL and YAHOO targeting.

Creating flows for engagement and boosting open and click rates.

Monitoring regular email delivery matrices and providing solutions for inboxing. Monitoring deliverability factors like DKIM, DMARC, SPF for domain reputation.

Helped in the setup of MAUTIC with the help of dev team to enable mass email sending.

Assisted in automation project for multiple domains for sending targeted emails as per user interests and last action.

Skills: Audience Segmentation · Drip Marketing · Email Marketing · Email Strategy · Email Campaigning

Email Marketing Specialist

Tutree, Inc.

Aug 2021 - Mar 2022 (8 months)

Implementation of email process

Preparing a strategy for email delivery and achieving conversion through regular bulk emailing Creating drip campaigns and monitoring the performance of campaigns

Suggesting content strategy and social marketing strategy to increase reach to end users

Managing end-to-end email activities including email template creation, segmentation and data maintenance using MAUTIC.

Automated email workflows and drip campaigns by using Mautic.

Involved in implementing an email process for a Synkdup -Community being developed by the organization A/B testing templates, subject lines, message content, CTAs, and send time. Creating segments based on user persona. Working with the tech team to resolve issues related to SPAM, email spoofing for cold emailing into the USA. Used Mautic to create trigger-based user email journey.

Assisting copywriting activities and providing inputs for preparing new content templates

Assistant Manager

Tripify (CheapFlightFares)

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020 (1 year 3 months)

Involved in end-to-end Email Marketing process. Designing Strategy and implementing email flow for all processes across the organization. Creating email marketing strategies for different part of user journey. Creating segments and lead generation using opt-in sign up forms by using MAUTIC.

Used Mautic for sending bulk emails and creating email flows for retargeting users.

Automation of sales process by using HUBSPOT and KLAVIYO

Creating newsletters and promotional emails for events and designing drip campaigns for user engagement.

Involved in product development of Tripify a travel community. Implemented email process and provided feedback for features of product.

Assistant Manager – Email Campaign Management & Deliverability

Tolexo Online Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2015 - Dec 2018 (3 years 7 months)

- · Creating and managing email campaigns for B2B and B2C
- Responsible for delivery of email messages as per delivery targets
- Collaborating with design & category team to develop email templates to improve deliverability
- Improve the quality of emails and maintain best practices as per industry standards.
- · Used Mautic for creating campaigns and sending mass emails via sendgrid SMTP.
- Analyzing email reports to strategies email segmentation and improving list
- Reporting OR/CR/ CTR

Lead - Client Servicing

Tinsel Town Media

Jan 2011 - Apr 2015 (4 years 4 months)

- Responsible for meeting clients and fulfilled their needs and requirements
- Presented various marketing ideas to clients
- Handled the responsibility of projecting budgets and schedules
- Managing and coordinating all product deliverables amongst cross functioning team (Design, Content) to ensure timely project delivery
- Handled the 360 campaigns for few Major Brands (HUL, Dr Lal Path Labs, Lenskart, CL Educate. Wonder Education etc.)

Education



鶅 Lucknow University, Lucknow

Master of Business Administration - MBA, International Business 2004 - 2006

Licenses & Certifications

mail Marketing - HubSpot Academy

Issued Jan 2022 - Expires Feb 2024 04d2eb114fab4fce91afc3725cb0bff2